# Cleisson Vieira Barbosa

- Rua Rosa Cordeiro, nº 420, 60812450 Fortaleza (Brazil)

Fortaleza (Brazil), 09 January 2017

Subject: Experienced programmer for Java Developer position

Dear Sir,

I would like to express my interest for a developer position. As a self-starter who's already had some strong experience as a programmer, I can offer to you:

- Four years' JavaEE programming experience with Eclipse, including JSF, Richfaces, Primefaces, Spring, Hibernate, Tomcat, Glassfish and Jboss servers, RESTfull WebServices and Android development
- Four years' SQL knowledge and DBMS Postgresql, MySQL, SQLite
- Hybrid mobile development experience with Apache Cordova, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, knowledge in JQuery, Bootstrap frameworks
- Usage of Docker, Jenkins, Jfrog, Maven, Git and SVN
- Usage of Redmine for manage tasks
- Knowledge in Python and Ruby
- Adoption of agile methodologies, SCRUM and KANBAN
- Usage of Linux and Shell Scripting

For the past four years I have been working with JSF in Brazil, one year in Teresina and three years in Fortaleza. I stopped to work between 2013 and mid of 2014, when I went back as Java programmer, after six month I was a internship supervisor and more one year I gone for developement manager position. For personal reasons, I'm not regular in my actual job, so in my CV this appears as "Independent".

I am qualified as Software Analyst and Developer, be a development manager was a choice made by need of management, once company almost has been ruined for bad geston.

The key skills that qualify me for Java developer are excellent programming logic, no problems with syntax and exceptions, good studying of Java documentation and frameworks, besides actualize myself in trends of IT.

I am enclosing my CV for provides additional information on my background and qualifications. I look forward to hearing from you as soon as possible to arrange a time for an interview.

Kind regards,

Cleisson Vieira Barbosa

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

## Cleisson Vieira Barbosa

- Rua Rosa Cordeiro, nº 420, 60812450 Fortaleza (Brazil)
- (+55) 86 999008786 (+55) 85 991963443
- cleissonvb@gmail.com
- kreyzon.github.io
- Google Hangout cleissonvb

## PREFERRED JOB

## Computer systems analyst

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### 01/02/2012-31/12/2012

## Computer systems analyst

CERCAP - CENTRO BRASILEIRO DE RECICLAGEM E CAPACITAÇÃO PROFISSIONAL, TERESINA (Brazil)

- ERP software development with Java (JSF, Primefaces, Postgresql) for Transit Department of Piauí (DETRAN-PI)
- Customer support

#### 04/06/2014-Present

## Computer systems analyst

Independent, Fortaleza (Brazil)

All activities below were done for HR Informática

- ERP software analisys and development with Java (JSF, Spring, Richfaces, Postgresql)
- Manager of developer team
- Trainee supervisor
- Customer support

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

## 01/02/2009-01/02/2012

## Technologist in Systems Analysis and Development

Institute Federal of Piauí - IFPI, Teresina (Brazil)

#### 08/03/2013-10/09/2015

## MSc in Applied Computing

University of Fortaleza - UNIFOR, Fortaleza (Brazil)

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

#### Mother tongue(s)

#### Portuguese

## Other language(s)

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
B1	B2	A2	A2	B2
A1	A1	A1	A1	A2

English

Spanish

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user

Common European Framework of Reference for Languages



#### Communication skills

- good communication skills gained through my experience as customer support

## Organisational / managerial skills

- good team-leading skills gained as president of Academic Center in IFPI during degree
- good organisational skills gained as host of the  $4^{\rm a}$  Academic Week of Informatic, responsible for receive public and announcing speeches
- leadership (currently responsible for a team of 4 people) in HR Informatica

#### Job-related skills

- good solver of problems (in begin, too many problems appeared and nobody knew why and I found the solution)
- good reseacher of news and innovations (I've experience in Java but I study Python, always I read trend topics of IT, like Cloud Computing, IA, etc and accompaned of evolution of tools and programming languages)

## Digital competence

SELF-ASSESSMENT						
Information processing	Communication	Content creation	Safety	Problem solving		
Proficient user	Independent user	Proficient user	Independent user	Independent user		

Digital competences - Self-assessment grid